<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?>

<feed xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#" version="0.3" xml:lang="en-US">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960" rel="service.post" title="Summitt Family Research" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960" rel="service.feed" title="Summitt Family Research" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">Summitt Family Research</title>
<tagline mode="escaped" type="text/html">Discussion of the Summitt Family History</tagline>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" rel="alternate" title="Summitt Family Research" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960</id>
<modified>2006-02-01T15:22:00Z</modified>
<generator url="http://www.blogger.com/" version="5.15">Blogger</generator>
<info mode="xml" type="text/html">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This is an Atom formatted XML site feed. It is intended to be viewed in a Newsreader or syndicated to another site. Please visit the <a href="http://help.blogger.com/bin/answer.py?answer=697">Blogger Help</a> for more info.</div>
</info>
<convertLineBreaks xmlns="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">true</convertLineBreaks>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113880732061796097" rel="service.edit" title="John Francis Summitt and sons" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-02-01T07:19:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2006-02-01T15:22:00Z</modified>
<created>2006-02-01T15:22:00Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2006/02/john-francis-summitt-and-sons.html" rel="alternate" title="John Francis Summitt and sons" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113880732061796097</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">John Francis Summitt and sons</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Well I finally got around to posting the pictures that Jack sent me.  Sorry it took so long.  You can find the pictures at <a href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/SpecialPages/JohnFrancisSummittandsons.php">http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/SpecialPages/JohnFrancisSummittandsons.php</a>.</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113734240850037406" rel="service.edit" title="Swank" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-01-15T08:25:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2006-01-15T16:26:48Z</modified>
<created>2006-01-15T16:26:48Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2006/01/swank.html" rel="alternate" title="Swank" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113734240850037406</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">Swank</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Information today from Rich Swank:<br/>
<br/>
<br/>1) Jacob Scwenk-1640 born in Germany<br/>2) Jacob Jr.-1673 born in Germany<br/>m. Catherina Mueller<br/>3) Son Balthsar Scwenk 12-23-1716 born in Germany<br/>Died 1763 Pennsylania<br/>m. Anna Elizabeth Durst<br/>4) Johannes/ John Swank born 1750<br/>Died in 1794 in Kentucky<br/>m. Rosannah Summit<br/>born 1754 died 1843<br/>5) Jacob Swank</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113734203985950005" rel="service.edit" title="PRIVETT" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-01-15T07:36:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2006-01-15T16:20:39Z</modified>
<created>2006-01-15T16:20:39Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2006/01/privett.html" rel="alternate" title="PRIVETT" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113734203985950005</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">PRIVETT</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Donna Walters has provided us a copy of an article from Yank Magazine dated August 17, 1945 that talks about Pfc. J.C. (Jake) Privett.  She sent this to the Quarterly because of the information in our online family tree listed below:<br/>
<br/>
<br/>[NI00041] Francis says J.C. Privett was the first person to die in WWII, widow was living in Blytheville, AR Killed in auto accident[Summitt_Oct2002.GED] Francis says J.C. Privett was the first person to die in WWII, widow was living in Blytheville, AR Killed in auto accident<br/>
<br/>Found on internet at url <a href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/FamHist/notes.html" title="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/FamHist/notes.html">http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/FamHist/notes.html</a>
<br/>
<br/>The article she found has been placed at <a href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/SpecialPages/JCPrivett.htm">http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/SpecialPages/JCPrivett.htm</a> for your reading.</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113672402998054712" rel="service.edit" title="Leon Foster" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-01-08T04:32:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2006-01-08T12:40:29Z</modified>
<created>2006-01-08T12:40:29Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2006/01/leon-foster.html" rel="alternate" title="Leon Foster" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113672402998054712</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">Leon Foster</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Just received word last night from my mother that Leon Foster died yesterday morning in Paragould, Arkansas.  He'll be buried Monday in Corning, Arkansas.<br/>
<br/>Leon was married to my Aunt Bonnie.  Aunt Bonnie was married to my mother's brother, Ray Frie.  He died in the mid '90's while Mary and I were in Nevada.  If I get more information I will post it.  I will post a obit to the SFQ site as soon as I can find one.<br/>
<br/>Leon, to my knowledge, is only connected to the Summit(t)s through marriage and a distant and tenuous connection at best through the Frie connection to the Summit(t)s but as my intention with part of this site is to cover not only the Summit(t)s and the Spotswoods but also the Fries and the Loves, I hope you will bear with my inclusion of someone like Leon.  Besides, someone tracing the Foster line may be able to use this information.</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113647770750294903" rel="service.edit" title="La Rue Summit Williford" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-01-05T08:12:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2006-01-05T16:15:07Z</modified>
<created>2006-01-05T16:15:07Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2006/01/la-rue-summit-williford.html" rel="alternate" title="La Rue Summit Williford" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113647770750294903</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">La Rue Summit Williford</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Received this email yesterday from Paul C. Summitt. As per Paul's request, as soon as the obit is found we are going to post it here on the SFQ site.<br/>
<br/>I just reviewed the latest rootsweb social security death index and found La Rue Williford, born August 30, 1908, died November 23, 2005, last residence Houston, Harris Co., TX, SS # 467-05-0339, issued in TX.  As you know, she was a Summit descendant of Francis Summit (1826-1892) who ultimately settled in Sims, Montgomery County, Arkansas with his large family.  Her grandfather was William Haskell Summit, son of Francis and Emaline Shaffer, and the only son who did not make the trek to Arkansas with the rest of the family and stayed in Texas. I do not have to remind any of you about the importance of this wonderful lady to Summit(t)(Sammet) family history research.  I would like to have her obit placed on the Summitt Family Research website if someone can find it.  I may write a piece on her for posting, but I have to review my extensive file on her--no one knew it, but she refused to give me permission a number of years ago to write an article about her for the Summitt Family Quarterly, but I collected the information, including pictures, anyway.I thought all of you might wish to know.<br/>
<br/>Paul SummittNiceville, FL</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113634969362404906" rel="service.edit" title="Dan Summitt's new book" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-01-03T20:40:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2006-01-04T04:44:09Z</modified>
<created>2006-01-04T04:41:33Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2006/01/dan-summitts-new-book.html" rel="alternate" title="Dan Summitt's new book" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113634969362404906</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">Dan Summitt's new book</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Glen Summit added this posting to the Summit(t) Research Group on MSN on Dec. 22, 2005.  Thanks Glen.<br/>
<br/>In October 2004 Commander Charles Daniel Summitt had his book published by Texas A&amp;M Press. Here is a summary.<br/>
<br/>Tales of a Cold War SubmarinerDan Summitt<br/>Though Dan Summitt retired from the U.S Navy years ago, he still regrets not receiving clearance to fill a submarine missile tube with thirty-five thousand pounds of wet grits and launch it at a very pesky Russian spy ship. In Tales of a Cold War Submariner, Summitt tells the story of hismilitary career, proving that navy life at the height of the Cold War ascommander of two nuclear submarines kept him on his toes. He relates his work with Adm. Hyman Rickover, recounts the efforts to stay undetected while patrolling for Soviet submarines, and sharesthe everyday dangers faced by a submarine crew. Summitt graduated from the Naval Academy in 1947, entered Submarine School, and rose to become deputy chief of staff for the commander of the Submarine Force Atlantic Fleet and chief of staff for the Submarine Flotilla 8. He served as commander of the USS Seadragon on its secret mission to the North Pole, where he rendezvoused with the USS Skate to conduct experiments under the ice. Summitt later took command of the USS Alexander Hamilton, one of forty-one Polaris-class nuclear submarines, which carried sixteen thirty-five-foot-tall missiles. Summitt takes the reader ona tour of this vessel, describing daily life and the routine and not-so-routine missions in close quarters with no outside contact for days or even months. Through it all, the fear of mechanical malfunctions, detection, or imminent attack always lingered. Summitt's anecdotes and descriptions capture this tense era in history.<br/>_________________________________________________________<br/>DAN SUMMITT retired in 1974 and now makes his home in San Antonio, Texas.</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113630513736551790" rel="service.edit" title="Civil War" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-01-03T07:28:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2006-01-03T16:18:57Z</modified>
<created>2006-01-03T16:18:57Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2006/01/civil-war.html" rel="alternate" title="Civil War" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113630513736551790</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">Civil War</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Well the new year is upon us and <strong>
<em>One Man's Treason</em>
</strong> still isn't finished.  I have, however, started working on the book again.  Currently, I am doing research into the causes of the War and what the war should be called.  There are a large number of angry people still out there on both topics.  After re-reading some of my chapter I am of the opinion that this chapter will probably antagonize both sides of these issues but I also hope that it might make some readers think.  I really question if people think much anymore.<br/>
<br/>I've gotten a few emails recently from my Aunt Ruth, one of dad's older sisters, and am very pleased to hear from her and know she is doing so well.  She and my late uncle Carter stand as shining examples of what I sometimes wish I could emulate. They spent a good part of their lives as missionairies in Africa. I believe one of their daughters and her husband are over there now.<br/>
<br/>Back in the early part of December I received an email from a young lady who had read about Chad Everett Summitt having been shot in an article here on the SFQ site.  It seems she was a friend of his and had not spoken to him since 1998 and was wondering if he had survived.  I know no more today about Chad's shooting than I did the day that Glen Summit sent the article to me.  If anyone knows more please let me know so I can update these pages.<br/>
<br/>There was also another message asking if there were any connections between the Summit(t)s and the Shumates.<br/>
<br/>Well, that's about it for now.  Good luck to everyone with the new year.<br/>
<br/>paul</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/20159960/113544537914065298" rel="service.edit" title="First things First" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>Paul</name>
</author>
<issued>2005-12-24T09:26:00-08:00</issued>
<modified>2005-12-24T20:47:26Z</modified>
<created>2005-12-24T17:29:39Z</created>
<link href="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org/2005/12/first-things-first.html" rel="alternate" title="First things First" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-20159960.post-113544537914065298</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">First things First</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://www.summittfamilyquarterly.org" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Well, it's Christmas Eve, 2005. We quit publishing the printed version of the Quarterly at the end of last year. I've decided to start publishing this blog about the family history here on the site instead. I miss writing about the family history and this seems to be one avenue of doing so again.<br/>     I recently received a set of pictures from Jack Summitt of Francis "Frank" Summitt and his sons.  As soon as I have a few minutes I'm going to clean these pictures up and post them here on the site for everyone to look at.<br/>     My goal is to update my GEDCOM file here on the site also.  I've been very disappointed with Family Tree Maker lately.  So much so that I have not bought the last couple of upgrades.  After the upgrade to Version 10 my file became corrupted and none of the fixes that the company help desk suggested worked.  So I've decided to try and get back to a clean version and export out to GEDCOM and then maintain my files in another application.  Not sure which one yet.<br/>     I also plan to get back to work on the Cardwell Cemetary Project soon.  This is a data entry job that just takes time.<br/>     Anyway, that's about all for today.  Merry Christmas to all of you and please feel free to drop me an email and let me know what you would like to see here on the site.</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
</feed>
